Elizabeth Clift

Senior Software Engineer

Mobile: 07933164385 LinkedIn: elizabeth-clift GitHub: scliftas

Email: scliftas@gmail.com

Full-stack engineer with 6+ years of experience working on serverless JavaScript applications using Node, React, and AWS and leading teams that delight customers. I'm an autistic and disabled trans woman with a strong passion for promoting DEI and constantly challenging the status quo.

SKILLS

- JavaScript/TypeScript
- Node/Express
- React/Redux
- TDD/Jest

- HTML/CSS/SCSS/JSS
- AWS
- CI/CD/DevOps
- Microservices

- SQL/NoSQL
- Elasticsearch
- Agile
- Lean Development

EXPERIENCE

Learnerbly, Remote — Software Engineer

AUGUST 2022 - DECEMBER 2023

Working as a full-stack engineer in a **cross-functional Agile team** at Learnerbly I focused on expanding how customers manage their users on the L&D platform. A particularly significant piece of work was working with my team to completely reinvent the platform's financial model to give customers much more flexibility in how they distribute funds to their users. This involved very **close collaboration** with our **Product**, **Customer Success**, and **Sales** teams to get a full picture of the business model and understand what customers needed throughout every step of their journey with our product.

I also worked hard to drive change within the Engineering department regarding front-end development practices and **accessibility**. From the start I introduced **Storybook** to improve the development and testing process of our front-end components, and drove a shift to building much more decoupled and reusable components.

Kinetic Software, Remote — Senior Software Engineer

NOVEMBER 2020 - IULY 2022

At Kinetic I worked in a **horizontal team structure** to develop a **cloud-based**, **multi-tenant** rebuild of a legacy conferencing events management system in order to keep up with market demand and remain competitive.

I played a leading role in implementing a micro-frontends, atomic design based approach for the platform's UI, also building and consuming Backend-For-Frontends with Sidecars, Entity Services and an Elasticsearch cache driven by CQRS. This all ensured the platform would be robust, scalable and thoroughly de-coupled. I was the go-to for any frontend questions and mentored junior members of the team to get them up to speed with the architecture and tech stack, as well as setting the standards that were expected for frontend development practices.

This role was very heavily built on AWS microservices following Lean development principles and Test Driven Development. I collaborated very closely with engineering management and the whole Product team and was responsible for providing forecasts for development work when deciding roadmap objectives. I worked with leadership to plan long-term department direction to ensure we were at all times moving in the right direction and work was proceeding according to schedule.

Cappfinity, Remote — *Software Engineer*

SEPTEMBER 2019 - NOVEMBER 2020

Working in an enterprise-level agile team maintaining and refactoring a **predictive hiring application** used by many prestigious enterprise clients, built with **Node**, **React**, **Python** and hosted as AWS microservices.

My main focus at Cappfinity was on streamlining the entire stack to reduce cost and achieve **operational excellence**. This involved a multi-tenancy rewrite that **reduced operational costs by 70%** as well as broad infrastructure changes such as appropriately scaling EC2 and RDS instances, and ultimately moving those instances into one **ECS cluster** which was all orchestrated via **Terraform**.

Kaweb, Lichfield — Web Developer

JUNE 2017 - AUGUST 2019

Working as part of a small agile-based web design agency developing solutions for multiple clients, ranging from **legacy PHP** applications to bleeding edge **cloud-based microservices**. I worked very closely with customers to understand their needs and was responsible for **big picture planning** of projects and also regular **sprint management**.

Multiple clients at Kaweb had a need for web scraping. I took a leading role in designing and architecting a robust, flexible and fully configurable scrape engine that would aim to suit all use cases built with NodeJS/TypeScript, Puppeteer, AWS, MongoDB & Docker.

EDUCATION

QA Apprenticeships / Level 3 Software Technician

Distinction across 6 modules, including C#/.NET, SQL and software development methodologies (Agile, SDLC).

Bournville College / Level 3 BTEC Diploma in IT

Distinction* in 9 modules, including software design & development and procedural programming.

St Edmund Campion Secondary School / GCSEs

10 GCSEs ranging A* - C, including Computing, English and Maths.